Miguel Pinto

Harrison, NY 10528 | (646) 820-5885 | mosaicorange@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/mosaicorange | github.com/mosaicorange/portfolio

SUMMARY

Java Programmer and Military Veteran with a Secret Security Clearance and 4 years of proven experience in the United States Navy. Accomplished measurable results while leading teams of 5 - 30 personnel in a dynamic, fast - paced environment. Possess a comprehensive understanding of Object-Oriented Programming and Database Development. Managed risk upon multiple lines to protect assets, property, and equipment valued over \$2M while meeting the expectations of senior leadership. Possess extensive knowledge in Technical Documentation, Resource Allocation, and Corporate Compliance. Recipient of multiple awards for outstanding performance and professionalism. Career supported by a Master of Science in Information Systems degree and vast operational experience.

SKILLS

- Java/J2EE
- Project Management
- Technical Documentation
- Resource Allocation

- XMLHTML
- CSS
- Corporate Compliance

- MSSQL
- C#
- VB.NET
- Enhanced Writing

EXPERIENCE

WMG Inc. | Junior Software Developer | Peekskill, NY

June 2015 to August 2015

- Revised software stack written in VB.NET and MSSQL with Team Foundation Server
- Recommended methods to correct enterprise configuration deficiencies to achieve compliance with Security Technical Implementation Guides(STIGs)
- Coded standardized test cases in order to alleviate manual execution

Vital Care Services | Telehealth Project Manager Intern | White Plains, NY

January 2014 to May 2014

- Generated technical documentation that established a framework to provide unified design across platforms which provided for expanded feature sets for clinical and patient applications
- Revised web content and disclosure documents for improved clarity, professionalism, and compliance
- · Collaborated with partners to design promotional pieces, including posters, web content, and design layouts
- Contributed to corporate blog; reported company events and news trends in the telehealth field
- Published Research for LISAT 2014 http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LISAT.2014.6845208

AHRC NYC | Account Coordinator / Foreperson | New York, NY

April 2009 to September 2013

- Managed 14 facilities across NYC Area with 23 employees and 3 supervisors
- Supervised an HRA Building in Midtown with over 260,000 Sq-ft and 15 employees

United States Navy | Engineering Laboratory Technician | Goose Creek, SC & Silverdale, WA

April 2003 to March 2007

- Maintained and analyzed reactor chemistry and conducted nuclear surveys aboard nuclear submarines
- Maintained a Secret Level Security Clearance with enrollment in the Personnel Reliability Program (PRP)
- Ensured workers minimized radiation exposure and conducted semi-annual workplace safety training on radiation safety to 150 members of the work group

PROJECTS

- Developed a RESTful API that retrieved, parsed, formatted, and returned JSON objects using Java/J2EE
- Created a Java program that sorted, added, deleted, and searched linked lists with user provided data
- Wrote a C# application to parse XML data and return an HTML file with precise calculations
- Developed a 3NF MSSQL database Server, which implemented triggers and stored procedures
- Made an Android App for rock, paper, scissors and an image viewer
- Optimized an Android app that monitors resources to include methods to terminated background processes
- Explored viable methods of implementing common browser extensions in order to reduce network security risks associated with employees' browsing habits

EDUCATION

Pace University, Seidenberg School of CSIS, Pleasantville, NY Master of Science in Information Systems

Pace University, Seidenberg School of CSIS, Pleasantville, NY

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems

August 2016

December 2014

HONORS

Society of Fellows of Dyson College of Arts & Sciences | Tau Sigma National Honor Society | SALUTE Veterans National Honor Society | Golden Key International Honor Society | Upsilon Pi Epsilon International Honor Society for the Computing & Information Disciplines | Alpha Chi National College Honor Society